# 这个大鲤鱼首先我们先拍下它的头
Let’s first knock on the head of this big carp
# 好 我们现在开它的肚
Alright, now we open the belly
# 可以慢慢走几下
We can make some slices carefully
# 不要着急
Don’t rush
# 然后再反过来往外面这样子刷一下
Then turn it round, and slice it
# 轻轻地把它给扣下来
Remove it gently
# 这是它的肠子
This is the intestine
# 肠子加鱼胆
Intestine and gallbladder
# 然后我们把它的油给取下来
Then we take the fat out
# 油取下来了之后再清洗干净就可以了
The fat just needs some rinses after taken out
# 然后我们在去除这个鱼鳃的时候
When we remove the gills
# 用两根手指这样插进去
Stick two fingers in like this
# 大拇指掐断它的鱼鳃
Nip off the gill with your thumb
# 掐断上面的
Nip the upper part of the gill off
# 好 下来之后然后直接掐断
Alright, just nip it off like this
# 翻过来的时候我们再换一只手
Flip it, and then use the other hand
# 右手扣右边的鳃左手扣左边的鳃
Right hand for the right gill, and left hand for the left gill
# 然后这样子扣下来
And then pinch them out like this
# 然后清洗一下就可以了
And then we just rinse it
# 开始来（分）解这个鱼
Now we start to fillet the fish
# 从尾部下刀
Start cutting from the tail
# 一刀一刀的往上面走
Knife it all the way up
# 贴着骨头往上面走
All the way up, staying tight to the bones
# 好 我们这个已经走上来了
Good. Now we have gone to the top
# 有很多粉丝朋友他在起这个鱼的时候
Many followers and friends are filleting fish like this
# 刀他是往上面这样子走的
Their knifes are pointing upwards
# 其实我们不能那样子
Actually, we shouldn’t do that
# 刀一定要平起来 往下面倾斜一点点
The knife must lie flat, and slants down slightly
# 往上面剔骨
when filleting the fish
# 因为你如果不往下面的话这个肉
If you don’t point the knife downwards
# 基本上就留在鱼上面去了
A lot of meat will be left on the fish
# 就留到了骨头上面
Will be left on the bone
# 我们可以看一下
Now let’s take a look
# 这个骨头
Look at the spine
# 片过来的时候一定要贴着这个骨头走
When filleting, the knife must stay tight to the spine
# 要不然就看不到肉了
Or you don’t get any meat
# 鱼片就起不下来
The fillet can’t be taken off
# 一刀一刀的往下面剁
Chop the head apart like this
# 然后就把它剁开了
So we have chopped it up
# 起鱼片的话我们首先把刀比到这个鱼刺这里
To make fish slices, put the knife next to the rib bones
# 推一刀慢慢地推
Push the knife slowly
# 慢慢推
Push it gently
# 然后到下面的时候再换一个角度再往下面走
When reaching the lower part, change the direction and keep going
# 这样子往下面走
Go all the way down like this
# 然后这边再回转来
Then here, cut it backwards
# 再上来
Moving up
# 再下去上来
And down, and then up
# 再下去
And down
# 慢慢的慢慢的
Keep it slow
# 靠这个刀慢慢的走位
Move the knife gently and accurately
# 片鱼的时候我们也要把这个下面擦干净
While slicing the fish, we need to clean up the cutting board
# 就是防止它有水
Don’t leave any water there
# 有水的话鱼会滑
With water, the fish may slip away
# 我们这个鱼片好了之后加点盐进来
Now we’ve done the slicing, add some salt
# 抓一下
Mix it
# 少加点盐
Not too much salt
# 这个鱼骨跟鱼片也抓点盐
Add some salt to the fish bones and tail, too
# 抓完了之后再用清水洗
And then rinse it in water
# 放上香菜就可以准备吃水煮鱼了
Add some cilantro, then we can enjoy our “Shuizhuyu” dish
# 这是鱼片
These are fish slices
# 有凳子你们不坐着吃啊
We have seats. You guys don’t take a seat?
# 站着多吃点撒
I can eat more when standing
# 坐都干啥子哦 坐都矮得很
Why would I sit down? It will be too low
# 嗯 好吃
Hmm, delicious
# 大家在家里面可以试一下
Guys, you can try it at home
# 有几斤嘛这个鱼
How heavy was the fish?
# 漆二娃买回来她给我说8斤
Qi Erwa bought it. She told me it’s 8 jin (=4kg)
# 我当真以为有8斤
I thought it was really 8 jin
# 真的8斤啊
8 jin? For real?
# 她吃了3斤的回扣
She took 3 jin as a kickback
# 她跑了路嘛脚步钱要撒
She ran the errand. That’s the errand fee
# 还吃了3斤的回扣可以
A kickback of 3 jin. Good
# 你看嘛一哈才8斤
Check it out. Only 8 jin
# 那是跑路费那叫回扣吗
That’s my errand fee! You call it a kickback?
# 一哈8斤就吃了3哒3斤的回扣
8 jin in total, and she took a kickback of 3 jin
# 跑路费
Errand fee
# 那是跑路费
That’s my errand fee
# 嗯 对头
Hmm, correct
# 你少吃点 跑路费你都吃了那么多的哈
Don’t eat too much. You’ve already eaten a lot with you errand fee
# 哦 你跑路费都吃了
Oh, you ate your errand fee
# 那是跑路费又不是回扣好不好
Come on! It’s just an errand fee, not a kickback
# 跑路费还不是要打折扣啊
Isn’t errand fee also a rebate?
# 这是芹菜是不是哦
Is this celery?
# 嗨呀 今晚上晚饭都不用吃了
Heya, we don’t need to have dinner tonight
# 今晚上还吃啥子饭哦
We don’t need dinner tonight, do we?
# 这就是晚饭撒
This is the dinner